<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-24T17:06:49-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Native Tree Mini-Museum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/24/native-tree-museum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Native Tree Mini-Museum" /><published>2021-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/24/native-tree-museum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/24/native-tree-museum.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nativetree_color.png&quot; alt=&quot;Full Color&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve been taking a lot of walks around the neighborhood and enjoying the scenery of my neighbors’ yards. I have particularly enjoyed yards in which it is clear the owners have deliberately planted native plants. In an area as drought-stricken as California, planting natives can help conserve water, reduce maintenance, and encourage local pollinators. Makes sense – the plants would have been living here anyway without us humans!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, along with some inspiration from the work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.ooo/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MICRO&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://biojamcamp.weebly.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BioJam&lt;/a&gt;, led me to wonder: how might we create a fun, interactive, community exhibit based on the celebration of native plant life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideation&quot;&gt;Ideation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began with some inspiration from the California coastal oak tree. Often when thinking of the trees of California one might first consider the redwoods, but its very vertical aspect ratio makes it difficult to properly display plants. The coastal oak tree is equally magnificent, and its wider branches make for a more accessible platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nativetree_collage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Planter Ideation&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the actual structure, I wanted to create something that balanced the grandeur of viewing a tree with accessibility so those of most viewing heights can enjoy it. I also liked the idea of building planters that emulated the rings of a tree and the wide reach of the coastal oak’s branches. Finally, I wanted it to be possible for a community with some handiworkers to assemble it themselves: imagine a beautiful afternoon during which members of the community garden or local elementary school put together their very own Native Tree Mini-Museum, and the kids are able to plant some native plants themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these requirements in mind, I began drafting 3D models using CAD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3d-models&quot;&gt;3D Models&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I had originally imagined huge rings of planters hanging like branches off of the main structure, I quickly realized that a massive round planter would be prohibitive to both ship and assemble. I thus altered my original design to be an octagonal structure – still quasi-circular in feel, yet able to break down into flat parts for shipping and assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nativetree_view1.png&quot; alt=&quot;View 1&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I realized that in order to actually enjoy the plants in the planters they could not be that high off of the ground. I spent some time familiarizing myself with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://access.si.edu/museum-professionals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Smithsonian’s guides&lt;/a&gt; for creating accessible exhibits, and came to the conclusion that the bottom layer should be 30” high at max and that there should be a ramp for viewing the top layer of the tree, with the top layer also being 30” above the ramp platform at max. I also incorporated signage for the various layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nativetree_view2.png&quot; alt=&quot;View 2&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my imagination, communities with access to branches from the local flora could incorporate those into the supports between platforms. This idea would need further consideration and discussion with local experts and community leaders on feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designing-for-transport-and-assembly&quot;&gt;Designing for Transport and Assembly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the above section, I created the shape of the tree with shipping and assembly in mind. While assembly would still require some tools and would certainly be made easier with the help of an experienced woodworker, I wanted to create an assembly with consistent, standardized parts that could pack flat into a shipping container and be assembled on site with basic tools. With some inspiration from a certain Scandinavian furniture company, I was able to come up with a set of standardized wooden boards, connectors, and slats that can (hopefully) be intuitively assembled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nativetree_exploded.png&quot; alt=&quot;Flatpack Exploded&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briefly, all screws and washers are avilable on McMaster-Carr and basic mechanical analysis shows that the fasteners and construction should easily support the weight of the wood as well as the dirt and plants eventually going into the planter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a first pass at creating an easy to assemble construction. I would want to actually interview and workshop with potential users before finalizing this assembly design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-plants&quot;&gt;The Plants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the fun part of this whole thing – the plants! Plenty of resources are available online (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnps.org/gardening&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;like this webpage&lt;/a&gt;) for determining appropriate plants for a native plant garden depending on the amount of sunlight and climate of your surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I believe that the most interactive and exciting way to go about putting the plant touches on this exhibit is to hire a local horticulturist or botanist and educator to instruct participants on the local flora and how it responds to the environment. That way the whole process can be based in the community members, leading to a greater sense of ownership and pride.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="design" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Work in Progress – Folding Rocking Chair</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/20/rocking-chair.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work in Progress – Folding Rocking Chair" /><published>2021-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/20/rocking-chair</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/20/rocking-chair.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/thumbs/20210220.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rocking Chair Render&quot; class=&quot;half&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day I was enjoying our rocking chair in the apartment when I came to two realizations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It would be nice to transport this experience to an outdoor gathering and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It would be nice if this chair didn’t take up so much floor space when it wasn’t being used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all led me to ask the question: how might we create a transportable, floor-space friendly rocking chair?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that this project is still in a relatively early phase, with physical modeling and kinematic design iteration still necessary. Still, I’d love to share where I am at right now, and showcase a little of my design thought process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rockingchair_collage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rocking Chair Ideation&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first thought was to create a folding rocking chair. Now, folding rocking chairs already exist out there. But there are a few obvious problems to me about the ones that are already out there. For one, they’re all aesthetically lacking. Most of the ones I was able to find have a plastic beach chair or camping chair look about them. While that does mean that they are made out of a sporty, light material, I would love to include shapes that feel more modern. Secondly, it is not immediately obvious how all of them fold. It is my belief that products ought to feel intuitive and natural when using them. For example, consider the basic, metal folding chair we’ve all experienced at various seminars and school assemblies in our lives. While it was not comfortable or aesthetically pleasing, it is very obvious how it folds up: one pull on the seat collapses the whole structure into an easily store-able form. How might we include that in our folding rocking chair design?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/thumbs/20210220an.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Chair Kinematics&quot; class=&quot;half&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly my first pass at this chair has failed on pretty much all of the requirements I set out for myself. It does not improve much aesthetically speaking on the already existing forms, and it has far too many degrees of freedom to be considered user friendly. I will need to go back to the drawing board. For now, I am considering the various forms of link kinematics I have studied as a mechanical engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I have the added constraints of the rockers on the bottom and my own desire to include an armrest, the links are going to be more complicated than your standard folding chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rockingchair_more.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;More Ideas&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option is to &lt;em&gt;break out of the standard folding chair form entirely&lt;/em&gt;. Could a rocking chair that accordions on itself across its midline be feasible here? This is another interesting possibility I might explore further. One question would be how to create an accordion chair that minimizes material (for lower weight) and can also stand up to the possible fatigue resulting from constantly being bent and then widened again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, this project would benefit greatly from physical iteration in addition to computer modeling. Unfortunately, due COVID19, I do not have access to the makerspaces I might normally have. Instead, I may make some cardboard models in the future as a way of physically prototyping in the current constraints of life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="design" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recovered Art</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/04/recovered-art.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recovered Art" /><published>2021-02-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-02-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/04/recovered-art</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/04/recovered-art.html">&lt;p&gt;I used to paint a lot, and recently uncovered some watercolors I did several years ago. Who knows - maybe this will inspire me to get back into physical arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/recoveredpainting.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Watercolor&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="painting" /><category term="art" /><summary type="html">I used to paint a lot, and recently uncovered some watercolors I did several years ago. Who knows - maybe this will inspire me to get back into physical arts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Just a fun goose drawing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/26/goose-drawing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just a fun goose drawing" /><published>2021-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/26/goose-drawing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/26/goose-drawing.html">&lt;p&gt;There’s honestly nothing science-y and nothing to explain with this bad boy. It’s just a fun goose drawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/thumbs/20210126.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bernice the Goose&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="digital-illustration" /><category term="art" /><summary type="html">There’s honestly nothing science-y and nothing to explain with this bad boy. It’s just a fun goose drawing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Commuting &amp;amp; Income in the Bay Area</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/27/bay-commute.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Commuting &amp; Income in the Bay Area" /><published>2020-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/27/bay-commute</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/27/bay-commute.html">&lt;p&gt;I never did finish this, but I probably won’t so I’m putting it out there now. Note: you may need to fiddle with the width of your browser window for the figure to be correctly aligned (all maps should be in a single row).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;module&quot;&gt;
    // Load the Observable runtime and inspector.
    import {Runtime, Inspector} from &quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@observablehq/runtime@4/dist/runtime.js&quot;;
    import notebook from &quot;https://api.observablehq.com/@wingsumlaw/congestion-commute-time-and-median-income.js?v=3&quot;;

    const renders = {
        &quot;viewof yr&quot;: &quot;viewof-yr&quot;,
        &quot;bayMap&quot;: &quot;bayMap&quot;,
        &quot;legends&quot;: &quot;legends&quot;,
        &quot;sub&quot;: &quot;sub&quot;,
        &quot;lineGraphs&quot;: &quot;lineGraphs&quot;
    };

    new Runtime().module(notebook, name =&gt; {
        const selector = renders[name]
        if (selector) {
            $('#20200727').append(`&lt;div id=${selector}&gt;&lt;/div&gt;`);
            return new Inspector(document.getElementById(selector));
        }
    });
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    button {
    background-color: #8a9bb8;
    outline: none;
    -webkit-appearance: none;
    -moz-appearance: none;
    appearance: none;
    opacity: 0.9;
    height: 30px;
    margin-left: 0px;
    padding: 5px 10px 5px 10px;
    border: 0.5px solid white;
    border-radius: 5px;
    color: white;
    font-family: Avenir, Arial;
    font-size: 12px;
    font-weight: 600;
    cursor: pointer;
    }
    button:hover {
    opacity: 0.7;
    }
    .inputGrid {
    display: inline-block;
    margin: 2px;
    }
    input {
    width: 100px!important;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;20200727&quot; class=&quot;full-width&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data all comes from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vitalsigns.mtc.ca.gov/data-center&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Metropolitan Transportation Commission of California&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the whole notebook on &lt;a href=&quot;https://observablehq.com/@wingsumlaw/congestion-commute-time-and-median-income&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Observablehq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="data-viz" /><category term="d3-js" /><category term="incomplete" /><summary type="html">I never did finish this, but I probably won’t so I’m putting it out there now. Note: you may need to fiddle with the width of your browser window for the figure to be correctly aligned (all maps should be in a single row).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Viscoelasticity &amp;amp; Plasticity, Visualized</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/01/viscoelasticity-plasticity-visualized.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Viscoelasticity &amp; Plasticity, Visualized" /><published>2020-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/01/viscoelasticity-plasticity-visualized</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/01/viscoelasticity-plasticity-visualized.html">&lt;p&gt;Elasticity, viscosity, and plasticity are important material parameters. But what do they actually look like? And why should biologists care about these properties?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is an interactive exploration of the ways we mathematically describe viscoelasticity and plasticity. Please note that this demonstration is geared toward those who have studied &lt;em&gt;college level mechanics of materials&lt;/em&gt;. The math could be quite difficult if you haven’t taken it before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;output-of-a-bingham-plastic--standard-linear-solid-sls-model&quot;&gt;Output of a Bingham Plastic + Standard Linear Solid (SLS) Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We represent the different parameters of a material as a series of dashpots and springs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;yield stress&lt;/strong&gt; of a material is the stress at which a material will begin to deform plastically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The elastic nature of a material is represented by &lt;strong&gt;springs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The viscous nature of a material is represented by &lt;strong&gt;dashpots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiment with different material parameters by fiddling with the sliders below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;module&quot;&gt;
    // Load the Observable runtime and inspector.
    import {Runtime, Inspector} from &quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@observablehq/runtime@4/dist/runtime.js&quot;;
    import notebook from &quot;https://api.observablehq.com/@wingsumlaw/viscoelasticity-plasticity-visualized.js?v=3&quot;;

    const renders = {
        &quot;viewof inputs&quot;: &quot;viewof-inputs&quot;,
        &quot;intro2&quot;: &quot;intro2&quot;,
        &quot;anim&quot;: &quot;anim&quot;,
        &quot;materials&quot;: &quot;materials&quot;,
        &quot;examples&quot;: &quot;examples&quot;,
        &quot;materials2&quot;: &quot;materials2&quot;,
        &quot;creepExample&quot;: &quot;creepExample&quot;,
        &quot;materials3&quot;: &quot;materials3&quot;,
        &quot;biology&quot;: &quot;biology&quot;,
        &quot;biology2&quot;: &quot;biology2&quot;,
        &quot;cellAnim&quot;: &quot;cellAnim&quot;,
        &quot;biology3&quot;: &quot;biology3&quot;,
        &quot;model&quot;: &quot;model&quot;,
        &quot;eq&quot;: &quot;eq&quot;,
        &quot;model2&quot;: &quot;model2&quot;,
        &quot;circuit&quot;: &quot;circuit&quot;,
        &quot;model3&quot;: &quot;model3&quot;,
        &quot;eq2&quot;: &quot;eq2&quot;,
        &quot;model4&quot;: &quot;model4&quot;,
        &quot;eq3&quot;: &quot;eq3&quot;,
        &quot;model5&quot;: &quot;model5&quot;,
        &quot;eq4&quot;: &quot;eq4&quot;,
        &quot;eq5&quot;: &quot;eq5&quot;
    };

    new Runtime().module(notebook, name =&gt; {
        const selector = renders[name]
        if (selector) {
            $('#20200301').append(`&lt;div id=${selector}&gt;&lt;/div&gt;`);
            return new Inspector(document.getElementById(selector));
        }
    });
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    button {
    background-color: #8a9bb8;
    outline: none;
    -webkit-appearance: none;
    -moz-appearance: none;
    appearance: none;
    opacity: 0.9;
    height: 30px;
    margin-left: 0px;
    padding: 5px 10px 5px 10px;
    border: 0.5px solid white;
    border-radius: 5px;
    color: white;
    font-family: Avenir, Arial;
    font-size: 12px;
    font-weight: 600;
    cursor: pointer;
    }
    button:hover {
    opacity: 0.7;
    }
    .inputGrid {
    display: inline-block;
    margin: 2px;
    }
    input {
    width: 100px!important;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;20200301&quot; class=&quot;full-width&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the whole notebook on &lt;a href=&quot;https://observablehq.com/@wingsumlaw/viscoelasticity-plasticity-visualized&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Observablehq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="data-viz" /><category term="d3-js" /><summary type="html">Elasticity, viscosity, and plasticity are important material parameters. But what do they actually look like? And why should biologists care about these properties?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CrossRef Publications Over Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/02/18/publications.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CrossRef Publications Over Time" /><published>2020-02-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/02/18/publications</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/02/18/publications.html">&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to learn d3.js and how to use an API, I created a graph that depicts journal article trends on CrossRef.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;module&quot;&gt;

// Load the Observable runtime and inspector.
import {Runtime, Inspector} from &quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@observablehq/runtime@4/dist/runtime.js&quot;;
import notebook from &quot;https://api.observablehq.com/@wingsumlaw/learning-basic-d3-js-api-utilisation-using-the-crossref-api.js?v=3&quot;;

const renders = {
    &quot;intro&quot;: &quot;intro&quot;,
    &quot;viewof f&quot;: &quot;viewof-f&quot;,
    &quot;legend&quot;: &quot;legend&quot;,
    &quot;chart&quot;: &quot;chart&quot;,
    &quot;moreInfo&quot;: &quot;moreInfo&quot;
};

new Runtime().module(notebook, name =&gt; {
    const selector = renders[name]
  if (selector) {
    return new Inspector(document.getElementById(selector));
  }
});

&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;20200218&quot; class=&quot;full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;viewof-f&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;legend&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;chart&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;moreInfo&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the whole notebook on &lt;a href=&quot;https://observablehq.com/@wingsumlaw/learning-basic-d3-js-api-utilisation-using-the-crossref-api&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Observablehq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="data-viz" /><category term="d3-js" /><category term="incomplete" /><summary type="html">In an attempt to learn d3.js and how to use an API, I created a graph that depicts journal article trends on CrossRef.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Floral Uterus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/30/floral-uterus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Floral Uterus" /><published>2020-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/30/floral-uterus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/30/floral-uterus.html">&lt;p&gt;After starting graduate school, I became interested in the pathogenesis of endometriosis. I have now started a project studying the role of cell invasion through other cells in endometriosis. And sometimes, I like to make art tangentially related to whatever I’m contemplating in the lab. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/floraluterus.png&quot; alt=&quot;Floral Uterus&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="digital-illustration" /><category term="art" /><summary type="html">After starting graduate school, I became interested in the pathogenesis of endometriosis. I have now started a project studying the role of cell invasion through other cells in endometriosis. And sometimes, I like to make art tangentially related to whatever I’m contemplating in the lab. Enjoy!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Post, Worst Post?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/27/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post, Worst Post?" /><published>2020-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/27/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/27/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Back in August of last year, I drew a basic illustration depicting the menstrual cycle. It has since become a main feature on all of my web presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/home.png&quot; alt=&quot;Menstrual Cycle&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school, I loved illustration and design. But because of some combination of lack of time, supplies, and drive, that hobby has since been neglected. Every few months I feel a renewed desire to get back into it, but it has yet to stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aformentioned illustration was my attempt at learning some digital illustration. Digital illustration has the distinct advantages of requiring neither consumable supplies nor physical storage space. Perfect for a student living in a studio apartment. As an additional perk, digital illustration is easier to share online. Yet everytime I try, it falls by the wayside while I focus on my academics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several months and multiple attempts at getting back into drawing later, I was listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2018/10/podcast-after-hours&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;After Hours&lt;/a&gt; from Harvard Business Review. In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/podcast/2020/01/tabloid-edition-fugitive-carlos-ghosn-and-royal-family-drama&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;episode released January 15th&lt;/a&gt;, Felix gave a glowing recommendation for the illustrations of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/FedericaFragapane&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Federica Fragapane&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly an excellent recommendation. I was both blown away and inspired by the density of information combined with the easy beauty of Federica’s creations. Below, I’ve included a graphic of hers describing the menstrual cycle. It is somehow both intricate and clear at the same time. And of course, beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B4AQ9-TBMn7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; margin-left: 10%; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B4AQ9-TBMn7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B4AQ9-TBMn7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Federica Fragapane (@federicafragapane)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-10-24T14:22:35+00:00&quot;&gt;Oct 24, 2019 at 7:22am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having spent a whole bunch of time flipping through (and fan-girling over) Federica’s work, I fell down a rabbit hole reading about data visualization. It’s incredible the number of resources and tools available out there for dynamic communication of quantitative concepts. I am particularly taken with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/d3/d3/wiki/Gallery&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;d3.js&lt;/a&gt; and the idea of creating interactive, web visuals. With this inspiration, I plan to get back into digital illustration and hopefully combine it with a new skill in using d3.js. And to make it official, I’m writing it down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Create at least one interactive visual aid explaining data from my academic work using the d3.js JavaScript library&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some subgoals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Become more comfortable using JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn to incorporate digital illustration with quantitative data visualization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Document all that online (check back on this blog later!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="digital-illustration" /><category term="art" /><summary type="html">Back in August of last year, I drew a basic illustration depicting the menstrual cycle. It has since become a main feature on all of my web presence.</summary></entry></feed>